Welcome to the terrific,
tumultuous tale of Dopey Dick.
欢迎来到精彩的地方，
笨蛋迪克的喧闹故事。
Call me Fishmael.
叫我菲什梅尔。
In my youth, I was an intrepid,
fresh-faced journeyman,
年轻时，我是一个勇敢的人，
新手熟练工，
looking from town to town
for any work I could find.
从一个城镇到另一个城镇
我能找到的任何工作。
Little did I know,
I was about to step in some.
我几乎不知道，
我正要介入一些。
Jellyfish jelly?
海蜇果冻？
Whoa!
哇！
Welcome to
the Jelly Squirt Inn.
欢迎来到
果冻喷射旅馆。
How can we help, me hearty?
亲爱的，我们能提供什么帮助吗？
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Ahh!
啊！
Have some jelly juice, lad?
小伙子，喝点果冻汁吗？
No, thanks.
不，谢谢。
I'm job hunting.
我正在找工作。
Might you lubbers
have employment
你可能会哭吗
有工作
for an able-legged young buck
with cash register experience?
对于一个双腿健全的年轻雄鹿
有收银经验吗？
No, no.
不，不。
Nobody touches
me money but me!
没人碰
我有钱但我自己！
Buy some jelly, or get out!
买点果冻，不然就滚蛋！
Here you go.
干得好。
Huh?
啊？
Psst. Hey, come here.
嘘。嘿，过来吧。
Hey, buddy.
嘿，伙计。
Shh.
嘘。
I've heard tell
that a boat called
我听说过
那条船叫
"Ye Olde Pineapple"
is shipping out soon,
《老菠萝》
即将发货，
and they need more hands.
他们需要更多的人手。
You've got plenty of hands.
你有很多双手。
I think I hear them
cutting the ship right now.
我想我听到了他们的声音
立即切割船。
Uh, thanks,
but I always get seasick.
呃，谢谢，
但我总是晕船。
I wouldn't be caught
dead on a ship.
我不会被抓住
死在船上。
I'm so sorry to hear that.
听到这个消息我很遗憾。
Shh!
嘘！
Got one!
有一个！
Egads!
哎呀！
I've been squid-napped!
我已经被鱿鱼打瞌睡了！
Yup.
是的。
The captain has
a special job just for ye.
船长有
一份专门为你们准备的特殊工作。
For me?
为我？
No, for ye.
不，为了你们。
Well, I do need a job.
嗯，我确实需要一份工作。
Ah, if I get seasick,
I get seasick.
啊，如果我晕船的话
我晕船。
Oh, don't worry.
哦，别担心。
I'll show ye the ropes.
我会告诉你们诀窍。
There's the big rope,
那里有一根大绳子，
the little rope,
小绳子，
the frowny rope,
皱眉的绳子，
the smiley rope,
笑脸绳，
and the licorice rope.
还有甘草绳。
This one's mine.
这是我的。
Ahh.
啊。
Do you know how to tie a knot?
你知道怎么打结吗？
No, but I'd love to learn.
不，但我很想学。
I'll teach ya.
我来教你。
Typical.
典型的。
Avast ye.
阿瓦斯特耶。
I be Captain Sponge-Hab.
我是海绵哈布船长。
Argh.
啊。
Hmm? Oh.
唔？哦。
I brought you all here
for a special mission--
我把你们都带到这里来了
为了一个特殊的使命——
to hunt down the great
white jellyfish,
追捕伟大的
白色的水母，
Dopey Dick.
傻迪克。
Was Dopey Dick the beast
who took off thy leg, Captain?
傻瓜迪克是野兽吗
谁砍掉了你的腿，队长？
Naw.
不。
My leg is all squeezed
into the handle.
我的腿都被压扁了
进入手柄。
I just love the sound
my spatula makes.
我只是喜欢声音
我的抹刀做的。
Uh...
呃...
Dopey Dick is a great
white jellyfish, lads.
傻迪克是一个伟大的
白色水母，小伙子们。
And he's the size
of a split-level condominium.
而且他的尺寸
错层公寓。
all: Meep.
全体：米普。
All that jelly!
所有的果冻！
Meep, meep, meep!
米普，米普，米普！
all: Meep, meep, meep!
全体：喵，喵，喵！
Meep, meep, meep!
米普，米普，米普！
Um, uh, meep, meep?
嗯，呃，米普，米普？
So keep your eyes peeled
for Dopey Dick.
所以一定要擦亮眼睛
为了笨蛋迪克。
And if ye spot him,
just give me a holler.
如果你发现他，
给我喊一声。
Yes, just like that.
是的，就这样。
That is exactly what you should
do when you actually see him.
这正是你应该做的
当你真正见到他时才做。
Dopey Dick.
傻迪克。
Doy, doy, doy, doy.
多伊，多伊，多伊，多伊。
Doy, doy, doy.
多伊，多伊，多伊。
Jellyfish be dumb.
水母都傻了
Chase that snow-hilled hump!
追逐那个雪山驼峰！
You, in the smart wool cap,
I have a special job for ye.
戴着漂亮羊毛帽的你，
我有一项特别的工作要交给你。
Uh, I be ready.
呃，我准备好了。
What is it?
它是什么？
Whoa. Oh!
哇哦。哦！
This is the special job?
这就是特殊的工作吗？
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
You'll make a great
sticky harpoon.
你会成就伟大的
粘鱼叉。
Fire!
火！
Okay, now I'm gonna throw up.
好吧，现在我要吐了。
We got him!
我们抓到他了！
Doy, doy, doy, doy, doy, doy.
多伊，多伊，多伊，多伊，多伊，多伊。
Meep!
米普！
He's got us!
他抓住了我们！
Whoa!
哇！
Meep!
米普！
Oh, please slow down,
Dopey Dick!
噢，请慢一点，
笨蛋迪克！
I don't have anything
left to throw up!
我什么都没有
留下来呕吐！
Wait, I know how
to soothe a savage beast.
等等，我知道怎么办
安抚一头野蛮的野兽。
Ahh!
啊！
My ears are biting me!
我的耳朵快要咬我了！
Hmm.
唔。
Doy, doy, doy.
多伊，多伊，多伊。
Doy.
多伊。
Argh!
啊！
Dopey Dick cannot
resist the music.
傻迪克不能
抗拒音乐。
Quick, everyone, reel him in.
大家快点把他拉过来。
Doy, doy, doy, doy, doy.
多伊，多伊，多伊，多伊，多伊。
Now, me hearties,
comes the best part
现在，我的心，
最好的部分来了
of hunting down
and catching a jellyfish.
追捕的
并捕捉水母。
Spreading the jelly.
涂抹果冻。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊，是啊，是啊，是啊。
No, you sillies.
不，你们这些傻瓜。
Releasing the jellyfish.
释放水母。
Doy.
多伊。
Aww.
哇。
all: Meep.
全体：米普。
Fly and be free, Dopey Dick.
飞翔并获得自由，傻瓜迪克。
Doy, doy.
多伊，多伊。
Doy. Doy.
多伊。多伊。
Ahoy, mateys!
嘿，伙计们！
Nice catch!
不错的收获！
Now it's your turn
to release him.
现在轮到你了
释放他。
We're not releasing bupkis.
我们不会释放布吉斯。
Oh, I'm sorry, Cap'n.
哦，对不起，船长。
I'm afraid we're just
gonna keep Dopey Dick
恐怕我们只是
会保留呆呆迪克
and sell his jelly for money!
并把他的果冻卖掉换钱！
Doy, doy.
多伊，多伊。
Money, money, money,
money, money, money, money.
钱，钱，钱，
钱，钱，钱，钱。
How can he exploit
他如何利用
such a rare
and gentle creature?
如此罕见
和温柔的生物？
Dopey Dick is our friend.
呆呆迪克是我们的朋友。
And if ye think you're
just gonna swoop in here
如果你认为你是
只是要猛扑到这里
and put our friend in a cage,
把我们的朋友关进笼子里，
ye've got another thing coming.
你们还有另一件事要发生。
Right, me loyal crew?
对吧，我忠实的船员？
Huh?
啊？
Shiver me timbers.
让我颤抖吧。
It's a reverse mutiny.
这是一场反向叛变。
Hey, Fake-Beard!
嘿，假胡子！
Put this in your poop deck!
把这个放在你的船尾甲板上！
Wahh! Phew.
哇！唷。
Ha, ha!
哈，哈！
Ye cannonball is a dud.
你们的炮弹是个哑弹。
Wait for it.
等等吧。
Hungry.
饥饿的。
all: Hungry. Hungry. Hungry.
Hungry. Hungry.
全体：饿了。饥饿的。饥饿的。
饥饿的。饥饿的。
Hungry. Hungry. Hungry.
饥饿的。饥饿的。饥饿的。
Nematodes!
线虫！
Ahh!
啊！
♪ Wah, wah, waaah ♪
♪ 哇、哇、哇 ♪
We've got to save Dopey Dick
from them pilfering pirates.
我们必须拯救傻瓜迪克
从他们那里偷窃的海盗。
We're gonna need
a bigger pineapple.
我们需要
一个更大的菠萝。
Scupper that!
搞砸了！
Pat-Buck,
follow those bilge rats.
帕特·巴克，
跟随那些舱底老鼠。
Aye, aye, Captain Sponge-Hab.
是的，是的，海绵哈布船长。
Doy.
多伊。
Doy, doy.
多伊，多伊。
Dopey!
笨蛋！
Shh!
嘘！
Quiet, stomach!
安静，胃！
You'll wake everybody.
你会叫醒大家的。
Follow me, me hearties.
跟随我，我的心。
Hmm?
唔？
Hmm.
唔。
Meep. Meep. Meep.
米普。米普。米普。
Shh.
嘘。
Shh!
嘘！
Who's there?
谁在那里？
Oh, it's you, honey.
哦，是你，亲爱的。
That was close.
那很接近了。
- Shh.
- Sorry.
- 嘘。
- 对不起。
Doy.
多伊。
Doy. Doy.
多伊。多伊。
Doy, doy, doy!
多伊，多伊，多伊！
Sit tight, Dopey.
坐稳了，傻瓜。
We're gonna cut you loose.
我们要放开你。
Doy, doy.
多伊，多伊。
Not if he keeps
doing that, we won't.
如果他继续的话就不会
那样做，我们不会。
Doy!
多伊！
There you go.
就这样吧。
All free, Dopey.
全部免费，笨蛋。
Doy, doy.
多伊，多伊。
Doy, doy, doy, doy,
doy, doy, doy, doy, doy.
多伊，多伊，多伊，多伊，
多伊，多伊，多伊，多伊，多伊。
Ain't jellyfishing
wonderful?
不是捕水母吗
很棒吗？
Somebody owes me
300 tons of jellyfish jelly.
有人欠我的
海蜇果冻300吨。
I wonder if
octopuses give jelly.
我想知道是否
章鱼给出果冻。
- Do they?
- No!
- 是吗？
- 不！
Kind sir,
will ye take an IOU?
和蔼可亲的先生，
你愿意借条吗？
I'll take an eye...
我来看看...
or two.
或两个。
Hmm?
唔？
Doy, doy!
多伊，多伊！
Do ye hear it, lads?
小伙子们，你们听到了吗？
Do ya?
是吗？
Dopey Dick's song.
笨蛋迪克的歌。
We still have a chance
to catch him!
我们还有机会
抓住他！
Everyone, beat to quarters!
大家，冲进四分之一！
Meep!
米普！
Hardy har-poon, sucker.
哈迪鱼叉，笨蛋。
Doy?
多伊？
Doy!
多伊！
Dopey, no!
笨蛋，不！
Doy!
多伊！
Cut me loose,
you Dopey dunce!
放开我，
你这个笨蛋！
For hate's sake,
为了仇恨，
we spit our
last breath at thee!
我们吐我们的
你的最后一口气！
Captain Sponge-Hab,
海绵哈布船长，
I don't wanna
work here anymore.
我不想
不再在这里工作了。
Doy!
多伊！
And that's how I became
the sole survivor
这就是我成为的样子
唯一的幸存者
of the hunt for Dopey Dick.
追捕傻瓜迪克的过程。
You weren't
the sole survivor.
你不是
唯一的幸存者。
We were all there.
我们都在那里。
It's my story.
这是我的故事。
I'm the hero.
我是英雄。
And I can end it
any way I want.
我可以结束它
我想要什么方式都可以。
Aww, Fishmael.
哇哦，菲什梅尔。
You're all buying another
round of jelly juice.
你们都在再买一个
果冻汁圆。
Yay! Yay! Yay!
耶！耶！耶！
Meep, meep, meep!
米普，米普，米普！
Ahh!
啊！
Those scurvy swine
那些坏血病猪
wouldn't know a good story
if it bit them on the--
不知道一个好故事
如果它咬了他们——
The end.
结束。